Inventory of the John Ehrlichman Papers, 1963-1982
Hoover Institution Archives
John Ehrlichman Papers,
1963-1982
88007
Ehrlichman, John
117 manuscript boxes, 20 oversize boxes 67 linear feet
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Photocopies of notes of White House meetings, memoranda, letters, and reports, relating primarily to Nixon administration domestic policy, policy relating to the Vietnam War, the 1972 presidential elections, and the Watergate controversy; and sound recordings of television news programs and interviews, Congressional hearings, and trial proceedings, relating to the Watergate affair. In part, photocopy.
Administrative Information
Access
Boxes 18-137 closed. The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1988, with later increments.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Location of Originals
In part, originals located in: National Archives, Washington, D.C.
Access Points
United States--Politics and government--1969-1974.; Vietnamese Conflict, 1961-1975.; Presidents--United States--Election--1972.; Watergate Affair, 1972-1974.; Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1913-; Conservatism.; United States--Politics and government.; Phonotapes.
Biographical Note
1925, March 20 Born, Tacoma, Washington
1952-1968 Partner, Hullin, Ehrlichman, Roberts & Hodge, Seattle, Washington
1968 Director, Convention Activities; Tour Director, Nixon for President campaign
1969 Counsel to President Richard Nixon
1969-1973 Assistant to the President for Domestic Affairs; Executive Director, Domestic Council
1970-1973 Member, Federal Property Review Board
1971-1973 Member, President's Council on International Economic Policy
1976 Author, The Company
1976-1978 Inmate, Swift Trail Federal Prison Camp, Safford, Arizona
1978-1980 Radio and television commentator
1979 Author, The Whole Truth
1982 Author, Witness to Power
1986 Author, The China Card
Container List
- NIXON ADMINISTRATION FILE, Appendix A - Documents: Files (Box 1-3)
  Primarily meeting notes; also includes schedules, memoranda, letters, telephone notes, charts, reports and statements relating to domestic policy, Cabinet and Executive Department personnel, the Vietnam war (including the CBS-Westmoreland controversy over enemy force estimates), Watergate, and the 1972 presidential election. Arranged chronologically; see Appendix A for detailed box list (prepared by the Archives of Artists of New Mexico and the Southwest).
  - Press: 1969 Evaluation of Writers & T.V. - R. Z. Klein Cross-ref. to 6 mo. game plan (28 pages), 1969 (Box 1)
  - Connally-the econ. boss G. Sh. defer J.C.-anti semetic (2 pages), Undated
  - H. notes re: Trento Changes- Where H, C, E were in May, June (1 page), 1969
  - Rogers, (& HAK)Change E.L.R. (1 page), Undated
  - E's To-Do List (4 pages), 2/5/69
  - Burger Letters to Mitchell (6 pages), 4/4/69-10/13/71
  - Six Month Game Plan/Notes (10 pages), 7/69
  - Image Analysis & Game Plans (contents missing pages), 9/69
  - Haynesworth/V. Nam
  - Family, Reaction to Don's complaints, Move funds to Bebe (6 pages), 9/4/69
  - Rocky, Agnew, Senators by name,WWH-golf-other expenses (5 pages), 9/5/69
  - Demonstrations-R.N. Reaction, Personnel Shifts, Haynesworth (10 pages), 10/1/69
  - TT-Scott-Hruska-Allott Cook-Griffen, Harlow-A.G.-Young-Cook-Beaulieu-, E.-Symington, (Haynesworth: The War) (10 pages), 10/2/69
  - Anti-Symington Pincus/Paul (Notes), Strategy Committee (2 pages), 10/7/69
  - Haynesworth, DPM- (FAP), paucity w/Rumsfeld (3 pages), 10/8/69
  - Press-Planted Q's, Order Ford to Impeach Douglas (2 pages), 10/9/69
  - Haynesworth, qt. pressure/appt a jew (2 pages), 10/69
  - TT and Ash Council/Reorg. (4 pages), 10/22/69
  - J.B.C. Volunteers, R.N. & Rock Music, Fec.-A.B.-private writings, Myth of Independence (12 pages), 10/23/69
  - Agnew-schism (Notes), Kraft Hugh Scott, Press Handle w/cool contempt (5 pages), 10/27/69
  - Austin Geriatric Center/LBJ (9 pages), 11/69-12/2/69
  - Agnew trip (Notes), an anwar dilemme (answered) (6 pages), 11/14/69
  - JNM, RN mistakes-Abernathy-etc- (Notes), Speech writers-"moving power" (6 pages), 12/2/69
  - TT-Haynesworth Conf. (6 pages), 12/4/69
  - Fitzgerald to Bob (Notes), No budget appeals to TT, Tipping WH help (6 pages), 12/19/69
  - 3 bil. stockpile, AB-Alexander Tax reform, Veto Hew/WH Conferences (3 pages), 12/20/69
  - RN on The Press (5 pages), 12/29/69
  - Dept. Budget Reviews (Notes), Stockpiler (12 pages), 1969
  - Budget Outlook '70-71 w/changes, Asset Sales/Murphy Finch (3 pages), 1/3/70
  - Don to H. Kalmbach, WWH - Use of golf course, Hoffe (2 pages), 1/8?/70
  - Private Schools in South (Notes), SOTU, Cut overseas personnel (3 pages), 1/9/70
  - HAK opinion of Mayo (Personnel), LBJ, Helms must go, HAK's area-Reorg., DuBridge (6 pages), 1/10/70
  - SOTU (Notes), Leak parts (4 pages), 1/16/70
  - Memo to TT, Burns-say at McC dinner AB was 1st choice (Missing pages), 1/17/70
  - Carswell (Notes), Line for Cronkhite re TT (2 pages), 1/19/70
  - Black Panthers (Notes) (2 pages), 1/29/70
  - Southern Schools (Notes), VP Agnew (4 pages), 1/30/70
  - The Presidency (Notes), personality of Admin., Taft and T.R., Press and TV (5 pages), 2/2/70
  - TT Mitchell G.S.C.-Finch-E. (Notes), (Southern Schools) (5 pages), 2/7/70
  - Agnew health role, Agnew speech writer, (1 page), 2/11/70
  - School-deseg. Panetta (Notes), Econ. (TT ple.), Agnew, (3 pages), 2/12/70
  - TT + JE Hoover (Notes), *Hooverisms (41 pages), 2/26/70
  - Agnew (Notes), (4 pages), 3/8/70
  - FED, LAOS (Notes), Ripon, Ivy League, Finch, (4 pages), 3/16/70
  - "How the TT Works" (Notes), DeSeg Stunt-game plan (Start?) (TT BH E), Carswell, (4 pages), 3/25/70
  - Carswell, TT RK E, (3 pages), 3/26/70
  - Agnew-GSA-Eastern States (Notes), Carswell (TT, H, E, Woods, Warren), Peace Corps, (2 pages), 3/31/70
  - EMK (Notes), Douglas Impeachment, (8 pages), 4/16/70
  - HAK (Diary), Shows me Cambodia, Attack plans-, (1 page), 4/25/70
  - Economy-Rinfret (TT Ph.) Need spokesman,E get in, Bail out brokers (8 pages), 4/27/70-4/28/70
  - TT Walk pre Cambodia, JNM to treasury, (1 page), 4/28/70
  - Rogers opposed to Cambodia Maneuver, Pete Upset, PN looped/Burger brings note, (1 page), 4/30/70
  - re: TT Mtg w/Kent State kids (Notes), (4 pages), 5/9/70
  - Agnew re. press (Notes), TT pb., (3 pages), 5/20/70
  - Burns-penance (Notes), Weinberger ONB (TT E), Hak - NYC Speech orders, Cabinet / Hickel, (3 pages), 5/21/70
  - Cabinet for Nov. (TT.H.E.), Finch, Hickel Letter, (3 pages), 5/25/70
  - Agnew-DPM re, Black Violence, (Missing pages), 5/26/70
  - Hickel/TT: run for Gov. (Diary), (1 page), 5/27/70
  - Hickel-run for Gov., TT-Hickel-E, (2 pages), 5/28/70
  - Finch HEW, New Nat'l Party, Cabinet, Population, (4 pages), 6/3/70
  - Penn Central-Guthrie (TT-Flan-H-E), Weinberger-om B, (2 pages), 6/4/70
  - Finch gives up HEW, Successor Q, (1 page), 6/5/70
  - Agnew & Joe (Diary), Rhodes, Fresh, 6/16/70
  - Scranton Comm'n (TT-Seranton AG-Finch), (Kent State etc), marching orders, Joe Rhodes, (8 pages), 6/18/70
  - Agnew/Taft won't appear, 18 year vote Penn Central (TT-BNH-BT), Prime M. Wilson call (HE), (6 pages), 6/19/70
  - Agnew & WH Staff (TT E), Hickel, (6 pages), 7/7/70
  - DESEGREGATION N B (TT/VP/AG), Schools (K/RF/BNH), South, (23 pages), 8/4/70
  - Timmons Report on Senate (Memo to TT), end-the-war-ammendments, to for-aid bill, Saxbe story, Scott, Sneaky stories, (Missing pages), 8/8/70?
  - Budget (C.D.), Cabinet-Schultz-Morton, HAK, FAP, DESEG Housing, (6 pages), 8/9/70
  - DESEG-New Orleans Quota (TT Sh E), (5 pages), 8/13/70
  - Sol. Gen. Griswold, E mtg. notes, (6 pages), 8/18/70
  - Solic. Gen'l-Parochial, TT H Scott, H. E., (3 pages), 8/18/70
  - Parochial, DeRussey, OMB, Liberals, Congress & W. H. Staff, Mamie's dentist, (6 pages), 8/19/70
  - R. N. (Diary), Manson's, guilty, (1 page), 8/30/70
  - HAK not on TV (TT H E), Sex-Pot-Porno-Rock, Press, Agnew, (2 pages), 9/1/70
  - Freeze-out (Diary), Kevin Phillips controversy, Hickel, Romney, Morton, (3 pages), 9/10/70
  - The "Social Issue" (very N.B.), and our domestic policy-R.N. orders, (11 pages), 10/70
  - Origin of Controls (TT Sh. E), decides to can Hickel, Fear of Kidnap, (14 pages), 10/23/70
  - Hickel (Diary), Firing & after, (4 pages), 11/70
  - Agnew-TT supports line (TT VP), Campaign (P Buch), Economy issue, (7 pages), 11/1/70
  - Budget (TT Sh-CW-E), Cabinet-openings list (A/F one), (9 pages), 11/4/70 (Box 2)
  - HAK (Diary), cienfuegos briefing, (1 page), 11/5/70
  - Distressed w/ AB re incomes policy (TT ph), Polit. strateg. blacks labor, Youth, Catholic, Jews, Italians, (9 pages), 11/16/70
  - Prep. For AB mtg. & Nam speech (TT-economists), Controls, oil, money supply, (13 pages), 11/19/70
  - Burns Meeting, (4 pages), 11/20/70
  - Ost-out (TT Sh. E), Budget, Oil prices, (8 pages), 11/23/70
  - Economy (TT Economist), Davis Bacon, Nam Speech, Fed, (21 pages), 11/30/70
  - Budget-space (TT Sh E), Burns - a problem, (6 pages), 12/1/70
  - TT Rates the Cabinet, esp. JNM, (2 pages), 12/3/70
  - Reorg-Cab of 8 (TT-Sh-Harper-CW-E), Budget PR-, CIA SST rejected, (6 pages), 12/5/70
  - More Cabinet, tentative Shuffle/Mitchell, (3 pages), 12/7/70
  - Cabinet, JBC, Bush, Rumsfeld (Diary), V TT, Romney, (1 page), 12/7/70
  - TT feeling overworked, use VP more, Kennedy + CIEP, Blue LK, (3 pages), 12/11/70
  - TT-Burns-E, Burns, TT Fed be liberal, B-CEA Errs, Incomes Policy, PR & E, (7 pages), 12/15/70
  - School Vouchers, Poff, Burns (TT Sh E), Connally/Base closings, (3 pages), 12/15/70
  - Economy (TT Sh HE), Economists to recruit, (2 pages), 12/16/70
  - Burger, Back trouble-Ryland (Diary), Crt gossip, Sch case lobbying, (1 page), 12/18/70
  - HAK & Schlesinger (TT-Sh-H.E.), Budget, VAT, Burns, Trends in '72, (6 pages), 12/23/70
  - Connally (TT ple), Jewish hijackers (C.D.), Church & PR, 2nd yr.-CAB-Accomplishments, (6 pages), 12/26/70
  - P. Peterson Solomon (TT-Sh-E), 3d yr. be tough on Staff, Rumsfld. paternalism, Rev Sh/Peace Corps space, Nat'l, Nixon, (11 pages), 12/28/70
  - Budget (TT-JBC-Sh), VAT (CW-E), What mark will we leave??, Cambodia-bold-, Tax Ref - Reorg., (16 pages), 12/29/70
  - Welfare (TT-Sh-DPM), Disraeli (E), 3 Rabbis, (7 pages), 12/30/70
  - Hugh Scott, E mtg. w/notes, (3 pages), 1/5/71
  - Governors & Staff, NR-Nunn, Vat/Rev Sh, Connally, John Lindsay, Rocky, (7 pages), 1/5/71
  - Tax reform (TT-E-Sc), Cabinet reorg., Peace Corps, J.E. Hoover, (5 pages), 1/6/71
  - Medicine (TT E), T.V. Intellectuals, Hutchnecker, Life, Glasses, Unemp. & Glasses, Expansionist econ., (8 pages), 1/9/71
  - P. Peterson-orders for Budget, VAT, Alsop-feed, Game Plan-Drowns, (5 pages), Undated
  - No Contact for 2 days (TT ph), SOTU dictates (Protest Amnesty), - of - when, press confs, Geo. Allen, (8 pages), 1/12/71
  - E.'s to do List, (1 page), 1/15/71
  - Econ- (TT-Sh-McC), Controls - poll pro (E), Davis - Bacon - suspend, (6 pages), 1/18/71
  - Open Collar (TT TT-Sh-RF-DR), Staff & Cab - Spokesmen rules (CW-H-E), WH rooms - who can use - PR, (3 pages), 1/19/71
  - Commerce-Stans (TT E), Lynn, Anti-trust - What is policy?, CPI - RR, (5 pages), 12/18/71
  - P. Peterson - in gp. (TT-HAK-E), Connally (Agnew), Build for future, Burns - TT - Furious, Morton - ass (?) an, P. McCloskey, (4 pages), 2/20/71
  - Sch Deseg. (TT Sh E), 18 year vote, Burns - adverse, PN to parks, (6 pages), 3/8/71
  - HAK - resignation threat, Blair Hse, Rogers - Mideast, (1 page), 3/8/71
  - Cabinet Rump Session (TT E), Counter - moves, (2 pages), 3/18/71
  - Allott & Schlesinger (TT/H/E), Cabinet Cabal - CD not by divine right, Wilbur Mill's family in, Counter-moves, (5 pages), 3/19/71
  - Corps of Eng. (TT-Sh-E), Abortion, Welfare, Reorg., Rump Cabinet, (5 pages), 3/23/71
  - May Day Demonstrations (Diary), concentration camp, be sure some police are hurt, McGovern, (1 page), May '71
  - Pentagon Papers (Diary), J.C. To Be Econ Spokesman, (4 pages), June '71
  - CHINA, Perrinos dinner, Young to conspiracy team: (1 page), 7/15/71
  - Agnew troubles/Dump (Diary), J.C. N's successor, E to advance China / Finch leave WH, (1 page), 7/20/71
  - Hoover, (1 page)firing breakfast, aftermath letter, (1 page), 9/20/71
  - Krogh memo, How to screen s/ct, Nominees / Send Dean and Young, (4 pages), 9/24/71
  - Supreme Court (TT E), Poff, Powell, Friday, Byrd, (2 pages), 10/2/71
  - Supreme Ct., how Rehnquist, Powell chosen, (1 page), 10/25/71
  - Radford, Wellander (Diary), HAK, Moorer, (5 pages), 12/71, 1/72
  - Dep Sec Def - not P Fian, Mitchell, Kissinger - protocol rank -, (1 page), 1/4/72
  - WASAG leak - Radford (TT H E), HAK & Press, Prosecute Jack Anderson, (2 pages), 1/5/72
  - Burns-the pay Board-Pessimism (TT/Sh/E), Geo. Boldt, State dept. & Rogers, HAK on J. C. succeed - J.C. a gentleman, (8 pages), 1/18/72
  - Rizzo's support (TT E), Wilbur Mills-family on ple., (4 pages), 1/24/72
  - VAT-Back off (TT ple), CD, (2 pages), 2/2/72
  - Don N. - Marriotts (TT H E), Donny - Vesco SEC, (2 pages), 2/7/72
  - Don Nixon (Diary), Ed & Don Mtg., Fin details, Ed returns, (2 pages), 2/9/72
  - A. Burns - Showdown (VAT/TT/E), Rizzo (A/Fone), Jews - sly, (4 pages), 2/13/72
  - CABINET (TT Sh E), PENN CENTRAL, Connally - Lockheed, (3 pages), 2/15/71
  - K to be AG (TT/Kleindienst), Rel to Connally (E), Civ. Rts Issues (SH), Women judges - list, you fellows run the place - V TT, (12 pages), 2/16/72
  - Buchanen to resign (TT H E), Busing-Deseg, I.T.T., (3 pages), 3/6/72
  - I.T.T. San Diego (TT H E), Damage Control, K asked hearing, New Hamp. primary prediction, Flanigan to P Peterson - biz, (3 pages), 3/6/72
  - RN to Hoover, ITT document, Verification, (5 pages), 3/21/72
  - Cabinet - no more mtings., Peterson disloyal (TT H/E), flush FAP, Rev Sh. (C.D.), Paroch. Sch aid, cut ARTS, Higher Ed, MIT, Don't move left - McGovern will be nominee, AE1, Press-force feed (Colson) (assume this is all a reaction to a talk w/ C. Colson), Enemy, Create new establishment, Major Daley, Need for a new party, ITT - a smear, (9 pages), 4/21/72
  - Volpe, typical appointment, (2 pages), 4/23/72
  - A: 2 great inspirations:, Rizzo A's protege (TT Annenberg), Keep Scott out (JNM - E), -Calif. - Norton Simon, Daughter an alternate - Reagan, (5 pages), 5/9/72
  - Abrams - read Churchill, Geo. Wallace (TT/H/Haig), Protecting TT - keep girls home (Colson E), Fire Rowley, Gun Control, (5 pages), 5/16/72
  - Wallace Shot (Diary), J.C. leaving, (2 pages), May '72
  - W/G report, I urge JNM leave, CMG replacer, (3 pages), June '72
  - Busing - Moratorium, Parochial Sch - aid, DDT, Erickson or Justice, Ambassadors, (5 pages), 6/15/72
  - Death Penalty (TT/E/HAK), Bumper stickers (S. C), Buttons-text, (6 pages), 7/5/72
  - Control Colson (TT E (re: Gray)), Agnew & his staff (Dean/K/Liddy/), Reagan (McGruder), Overview-TT-vote of no confid. (TT H/E/McGregor), in JNM & Magruder Malek Timmons, (12 pages), 7/6/72
  - Watergate: Walters & Gary (TT H E), Campaign issues (SC), Woodrow Wilson-chippy chaser, Drowns to Ceylon, (3 pages), 7/6/72
  - Clark McGregor - P Gray/CIA, nover talk to TT re W/G (TT E), CIA - no interest (SC), (2 pages), 7/6/72
  - Agnew & press, Watergate: Holms & Walters (TT E ), Cover up (S. C.), Econ statistics BLS, (11 pages), 7/7/72
  - WGF-no coverup-full investign, no WH involvmt (TT E), Bitman (San C.), MacGruder resign sooner, Reps boycott all Cong. Comms., (2 pages), 7/8/72
  - S C explan., 6/23 Helms etc. (TT/E), (4 pages), 7/8/72
  - Jacobson of Texas, W/G Timing-post election (Kleindienst), Sloan. Stans/ Liddy/Jeb (Dean/E), TT pictures to RK Erickson, Vr Amendmt. / Jeb, (3 pages), 7/31/72
  - Kleindienst, JD, E, (3 pages), 7/31/72
  - Teeter-polls, Issues for '72, (6 pages), 8/1/72
  - Colson Staff list (Kenrli), (3 pages), 8/1/72
  - McGovern (TT), permissiveness-line, (1 page), Undated
  - Use IRS-O'Brien McGovern (TT/H/E), Football in desk drawer, Laird-rebelling, Romney, Erred in picking cabinet, (3 pages), 8/3/72
  - Romney/Wilkes Barre, Memo to GR; talking paper, (1 page), 8/10/72 (Box 3)
  - Discrim. Suits v LA. (Phone), Chicago, etc, Kleindienst, (Missing pages), 8/10/72
  - Romney letter resignat'n (TT H E), R's W.B. letter anquish, Let Rumsfeld go, Carlucci, Romney replaced with Van Dusen, Romney told not to go to platform Committee, A R Longworth -A/F one to convention, S. Alsop, RN's 4 Eulogies, (3 pages), 8/11/72
  - Romney report (TT Romney, Lincoln et al), on Wilkes-Barre, (10 pages), 8/11/72
  - Romney, TT Directive, Lenore's letter, Resignation, (4 pages), Aug. '72
  - TT Romney E / Romney W.B. report / RN-premonition, San Clemente / to leave 1/ will campaign, (2 pages), 10/31/72
  - Schultz-Walters (Phone), Re: O'Brien tax investig'n, (7 pages), 8/29/72
  - RN/premonition (Diary), (1 page)of assassination, (1 page), 10/31/72
  - Agnew-Indians (Sta), BIA Riot, (Missing pages), 11/10/72
  - Innaugural (TT/E), Restaffing, Ed, Julie, Colson, Innaug. Consultants A/Fone, (3 pages), 11/12/72
  - Hire Julie (TT/H/E), Agnew in '76 - won't help him, Budget-cuts (Camp David ), HAK is a rag mer. (* (scene)), Agnew-criteria-falls short-staff, Reorg-3 counsellors, Henry Jackson - Sec Def?, Restaffing, Rogers, (8 pages), 11/14/72
  - TT Ash/Malek Reorg-, H.E., Camp David (Ike), (3 pages), 11/14/72
  - Flanigan (Restaff TT H E), Rogers (CD Aspen), Klein, Rumsfeld, Malek, Morton, ELR, C Colson, (8 pages), 11/16/72
  - J.B.C. reconfirm judges every 10 yrs/Restaff (TT Weinberger E) (TT-Sh P Peterson E), Weinberger, Offer to P.P., CIEP not worked-the Hak problem (DOD-Richardson), (9 pages), 11/17/72
  - Restaff: (TT/Sh/E), Volcker (Dogwood/CD), P.. Peterson/shldn't stay - a Percy man, Flanigan, Casey, Dent, Rumsfeld, Walker, Bush, Weinberger, Report on Meany, Hodgeson, A secy Labor-ask Colson, (7 pages), 11/17/72
  - Bush / Restaff, Brennan (TT E then Rumsfeld), Rumsfeld session (Aspen Sh), (8 pages), 11/20/72
  - Bush to RNC, RN to RNC in '60 (TT/Bush/E), Margin over McG. greatest (Aspen), "The in Clique", Klein, Finch leaving, Dole out, (13 pages), 11/20/72
  - Morton mtg. - Restaff, Allott-flanked Rogers-Dole to go (TT/Rog Morton/E), Rush/H - Rush mtg:, BIA Reorg Proposal, (8 pages), 11/21/72
  - P. Peterson (Restaff), Rumsfeld (TT H E), Helms 60, Schlesinger, HAK - don't smile in pics w/Tho, NSC Staff, Klein-retire or usia, Cabinet, Simon, Cole, (9 pages), 11/22/72
  - Timmons probs, Dole must go (TT/Timmons/H.E. Dogwood), BIA problems, Hauge letter re W.G., (8 pages), 11/22/72
  - Eastland-keep Kleindienst, Klein-now / restaff (TT Hodgeson E), Hodgson, Rumsfeld, Don Rogers, (4 pages), 11/22/72
  - Romney out: terms, Volpe (TT E), Scali (TT Romney), Agnew (E Restaff), Indians, Kleindienst gone by summer, Rocky and JBC didn't want to be in cabinet, Don't sell yourself cheap, Laird, Sam Jackson, (9 pages), 11/24/72
  - Kleindienst 6 mo- (TT H E), Scali & HAK, Ambrose, Press Plan, (2 pages), 11/27/72
  - State restaff (Aspen), Blacks (TT/HAK/H/E), IRS, Sneed/Fay DAG, Nudge Douglas & Marshall off, Rizzo, Cutler. / Clifford on blacklist, Bush - TT will particip. in staffing RNC, (4 pages), 11/27/82
  - Gray/ill/ok, FBI leaks (TT/Kleindienst), FBI director (H.E), Justice Dept., Mrs. LBJ urges Harzog, Holdovers, Goldwater-Amb. to Mex 2 years, K want to be TT?, Ambition - fat rich, Clifford out, Cutler finished, Rogers-$10 mil, K leave-resign 7/, DAG - K: not Ambrose, (13 pages), 11/27/72
  - Bureaucracy (TT/Simon/E), IRS, Volelder, Cohen, Walker, Shultz, Don't be taken over by Wash. set, Foundations, Tax Reform, Tell Alexander, *Where to live-schools, (7 pages), 11/28/72
  - Impasse-DOJ cleanout (TT/Kleindienst/E), Dole-RNC-wants to stay (T/H/E), Kleindienst, Dent-Textiles, DOJ-Asst. A.G's, Dean asks help w/R.K.-, (7 pages), 11/28/72
  - Blacks, Ethnics (TT/Lynn/E), Cabinet-Dept to TT, Model Cities-flush, Ivy League, Jews, Biz council/break, Rocky & J.B.C., (4 pages), 11/28/72
  - Southerners (TT/Dent/Sh/E), Bix Council, Stans/P.P. weak, Commerce no longer puppet of B.C., "Biz people who stood up", Brennan, GM Wilson was right, W+P Controls-when they work, How to run commerce, The Team, For. Trade, Labor, Energy, Live in Country, Bush a prep classmate-P Flan also, Dean for DAG, Nixon Library-Hebert to Cal soon/Cushman help, (12 pages), 11/29/72
  - Blacks (TT/E A/F one), Griswold/Bork, *Drop Ellsberg case, Gray-JNM can't send to senate, *E run energy from WH, Black southern Fed. judge, (4 pages), 11/30/72
  - Ivy League 1.7%, Clean up Gov't (TT/Colson/H/E/), Give state to J.B.C. (Key Biscayne), 5th Circuit, Defeated Senators: Allott, Miller, Chaffee, Jas Rhodes, Congress in new term - Blueprint, DOJ-Santarelli Wally Johnson-David's friend, P. Flan not HAK do ambassadors, Gray, Morton, Scali, Wash. Post. Scaife offer-suit 1,000 days, Colson's staff after Baroudy, Southerner on WH staff, AEI-change, Agnew-no fund raisers, JBC moven't/6 mo./so CC not RNC counsel, A new political party, New swimming pool, (11 pages), 12/1/72
  - Ambassadors - tell Rogers, HAK not ultra viries (?!) (TT/H/E), DOJ changes (KB?), Webster/IRS, Rumsfeld/NATO/rankles, PP - No, R.N. Estate Plan, Herb Klein-trying to find a job, P. Flan, Sh fire IRS' Walters, Schlesinger on Intellig., Cabinet, Agnew on V. Nam, Congress, New Party, 12/2/72
  - Donny Nixon Jr. (G I Straub) (Cables-leaders), (10 pages), 12/4/72 mtg
  - Controls (TT/Sh/E), Food Prices, PR of Inflation, Phase III, P. Peterson, Rinfret, Labor support, Rev. sharing $, sh to Mills / Long, Trade, Monetary, For. Economic issues, World Bank, Cut UN ½, P. Peterson, Mode of departure, Russian Gas Deal, JBC in, others out, Rumsfeld - mistake, Goals of PS (?!) P P?!) trip, (13 pages), 12/5/72
  - Viet Nam Negotiations, HAK instructions (TT/H/E) (Aspen), (3 pages), 12/6/72
  - Florida lots-Tricia, Sinatra - Bicentennial (TT/H/E), Restaffing (CD?), Viet Nam - HAK, (3 pages), 12/7/72 5:30p.
  - IRS Grievences, C Clifford never audited (TT/Sh/Webster/E), Hating bureaucrats, Honesty, clean house, Pull files w/o Q-never improper, Sensitive Case Reps, E or Dean, (4 pages), 12/7/72 1:30p
  - P. Peterson, Rumsfeld (TT E), Griswold (Aspen), Sneed, (3 pages), 12/7/72 9:30 am
  - Georgia senate race, Herman Talmedge will deal (TT/Campbell/E), Agric. bureauc. go (Aspen), Weinberger conserv. Strategy, HUD dismantled, PR Plan-reorg., Finch-Hamlet, Krogh to Dot etc., *s/cr list - 2 Catholics, Morton temporary - Whitaker in, can't run anything, Interior restaff, Our men in the Depts, orderly control of Govt., Energy, OST - wither, LBJ - RN, Interior's problems, (15 pages), 12/7/72
  - Budget: Sale of Assets (TT/sh/Weinberger), CIA - Schlesinger cuts (Stein/Carlucci/Cole/E), Dod supplemental (Aspen), Dod cuts, OEO - can't cut out-strategy, services, ABA - never WH, Decentralize, 250 bil., Gt. Soc. over, Unemp. 5.2%, Controls justified-, Jobs programs, ZPG, 10 year Plan, "Nations decline when births decline", Who is reproducing? Demographics, Energy & populin projections, RIF, No exec. raises, space cuts, cuts, WH Staff-50% cut, (19 pages), 12/7/72